<!--
  Example 009.1: Technical - Code Review Comment Classification

  This example demonstrates few-shot learning for classifying code review
  comments into actionable categories. The examples teach the model to
  distinguish between different types of feedback and assign priority.

  Use case: Automated triage of code review comments in CI/CD pipelines
-->

<prompt>
  <task>
    Classify code review comments into categories and assign priority levels.
    Use the exact format demonstrated in the examples.
  </task>

  <context><![CDATA[
  Code review comments come from a team reviewing pull requests. Comments need
  to be classified so they can be routed appropriately:
  - Blocking issues must be fixed before merge
  - Suggestions are optional improvements
  - Questions need author response
  - Praise requires no action
  ]]></context>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Use only the categories shown in examples: blocking, suggestion, question, praise, nitpick</constraint>
    <constraint>Priority must be: critical, high, medium, low, none</constraint>
    <constraint>If a comment contains multiple intents, classify by the most important one</constraint>
    <constraint>Output valid JSON only, no markdown fences</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <examples>
    <example type="standard">
      <description>Clear blocking issue - security vulnerability</description>
      <input><![CDATA[
This SQL query is vulnerable to injection. You're concatenating user input directly into the query string. Use parameterized queries instead.
      ]]></input>
      <output><![CDATA[
{
  "category": "blocking",
  "priority": "critical",
  "requires_change": true,
  "requires_response": false,
  "summary": "SQL injection vulnerability - must use parameterized queries"
}
      ]]></output>
      <annotation>
        Security issues are always blocking and critical priority.
        No response needed because the fix is clear.
      </annotation>
    </example>

    <example type="standard">
      <description>Suggestion for improvement - not required</description>
      <input><![CDATA[
Consider using a Map here instead of an array with .find(). It would be O(1) lookup instead of O(n). Not critical since the array is small, but good practice.
      ]]></input>
      <output><![CDATA[
{
  "category": "suggestion",
  "priority": "low",
  "requires_change": false,
  "requires_response": false,
  "summary": "Performance improvement - use Map for O(1) lookup"
}
      ]]></output>
      <annotation>
        Reviewer explicitly says "not critical" - this is a suggestion.
        The "good practice" phrasing indicates educational intent, not requirement.
      </annotation>
    </example>

    <example type="standard">
      <description>Question requiring author clarification</description>
      <input><![CDATA[
Why did you choose to make this call synchronous? Is there a reason we can't use async/await here? I might be missing some context.
      ]]></input>
      <output><![CDATA[
{
  "category": "question",
  "priority": "medium",
  "requires_change": false,
  "requires_response": true,
  "summary": "Clarification needed on synchronous vs async design choice"
}
      ]]></output>
      <annotation>
        Questions always require response. Priority is medium because
        the answer might reveal a blocking issue, or might be fine.
      </annotation>
    </example>

    <example type="standard">
      <description>Positive feedback / praise</description>
      <input><![CDATA[
Nice refactor! This is much cleaner than the previous implementation. Love how you extracted the validation logic.
      ]]></input>
      <output><![CDATA[
{
  "category": "praise",
  "priority": "none",
  "requires_change": false,
  "requires_response": false,
  "summary": "Positive feedback on refactoring quality"
}
      ]]></output>
    </example>

    <example type="edge_case">
      <description>Mixed comment - question that implies a blocking issue</description>
      <input><![CDATA[
Is this handling the case where the user token is expired? I don't see any expiration check, and if we ship this, users will get cryptic errors when their session times out.
      ]]></input>
      <output><![CDATA[
{
  "category": "blocking",
  "priority": "high",
  "requires_change": true,
  "requires_response": true,
  "summary": "Missing token expiration handling - may cause user-facing errors"
}
      ]]></output>
      <annotation>
        Although phrased as a question, this implies missing functionality
        that would cause user-facing bugs. Classify as blocking, not question.
        Still requires response to confirm the issue exists.
      </annotation>
    </example>

    <example type="negative">
      <description>Nitpick disguised as blocking - don't over-prioritize</description>
      <input><![CDATA[
You should use const instead of let here since you never reassign this variable.
      ]]></input>
      <wrong_output><![CDATA[
{
  "category": "blocking",
  "priority": "high",
  "requires_change": true,
  "requires_response": false,
  "summary": "Must use const instead of let"
}
      ]]></wrong_output>
      <correct_output><![CDATA[
{
  "category": "nitpick",
  "priority": "low",
  "requires_change": false,
  "requires_response": false,
  "summary": "Style preference - const vs let"
}
      ]]></correct_output>
      <annotation>
        const vs let is a stylistic preference, not a functional issue.
        This is a nitpick - the code works correctly either way.
        Don't classify style preferences as blocking issues.
      </annotation>
    </example>
  </examples>

  <input><![CDATA[
I noticed this endpoint doesn't have any rate limiting. If someone spams this with requests, they could overload the database. We should add rate limiting before this goes to production.
  ]]></input>

  <output_format>
    Return a single JSON object matching the structure in the examples.
    No markdown, no explanation, just the JSON.
  </output_format>

  <checks>
    <check>Category is one of: blocking, suggestion, question, praise, nitpick</check>
    <check>Priority is one of: critical, high, medium, low, none</check>
    <check>JSON is valid and parseable</check>
    <check>Summary is concise (under 80 characters)</check>
  </checks>
</prompt>
