<prompt>
  <!--
    Example 18.2: Personal Development - Deep Work in the Age of AI
    Uses the longform template for comprehensive personal development content
  -->

  <task>
    Write a long-form content piece that dives deep into the topic below.
    The piece should be rigorous, coherent, and concrete.
  </task>

  <topic>Deep Work Practices: Adapting Cal Newport's Framework for AI-Augmented Knowledge Work</topic>

  <audience>Knowledge workers (developers, writers, analysts) who use AI tools daily</audience>

  <intent>educate</intent>

  <stance>optimistic</stance>

  <voice_and_tone>
    <style>Modern, restrained, and clear.</style>
    <avoid>
      <item>Hype and marketing language</item>
      <item>Productivity porn and hustle culture framing</item>
      <item>Vague generalities like "work smarter not harder"</item>
      <item>Overconfident claims without support</item>
    </avoid>
  </voice_and_tone>

  <source_policy>
    <policy>
      Reference Cal Newport's Deep Work framework as the foundation.
      Distinguish between his original concepts and proposed adaptations.
    </policy>
    <policy>
      Use concrete examples from software development, writing, and analysis work.
      Acknowledge that individual results vary significantly.
    </policy>
  </source_policy>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Start by defining "deep work" in plain language before extending it.</constraint>
    <constraint>Use the "attention residue" concept as an organizing framework.</constraint>
    <constraint>Address the paradox: AI tools both enable and threaten deep work.</constraint>
    <constraint>Provide specific, actionable protocols (not just principles).</constraint>
    <constraint>Include time-boxed experiments the reader can try this week.</constraint>

    <constraint>Introduce key terms before using them heavily.</constraint>
    <constraint>Distinguish between research findings and practitioner wisdom.</constraint>
    <constraint>Avoid name-dropping; only cite concepts/people if they add explanatory value.</constraint>

    <constraint>Use the exact section headings specified in output_contract.</constraint>
    <constraint>No preamble, no meta-commentary about the prompt.</constraint>
    <constraint>Keep paragraphs reasonably short; prefer clarity over density.</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <optional_context>
    The reader likely already uses AI tools (ChatGPT, Copilot, etc.) multiple times daily.
    They feel both more productive and more scattered. They want to preserve the benefits
    of AI assistance while reclaiming the ability to do sustained, focused work.
  </optional_context>

  <reader_promises>
    <promise>The reader understands how AI tools affect attention and can mitigate downsides.</promise>
    <promise>The reader has 3 specific protocols to try in the next week.</promise>
    <promise>The reader can design their own AI-augmented deep work practice.</promise>
  </reader_promises>

  <output_contract>
    <format>
      Use markdown with H2 section headings exactly as written below.
      Under each heading, write substantive content (not bullet-only sections).
    </format>

    <required_headings>
      <heading>Introduction and explanation</heading>
      <heading>Technique deep dive</heading>
      <heading>Pros and cons, when and where to use</heading>
      <heading>Use cases and examples</heading>
      <heading>Applicability and potential</heading>
      <heading>What's next</heading>
    </required_headings>

    <section_requirements>
      <introduction_and_explanation>
        <requirements>
          <item>Define deep work vs. shallow work with modern examples</item>
          <item>Explain why AI changes the deep work equation</item>
          <item>Preview the "attention residue" framework</item>
        </requirements>
      </introduction_and_explanation>

      <technique_deep_dive>
        <requirements>
          <item>The attention residue problem with frequent AI queries</item>
          <item>Batching vs. interleaving AI assistance</item>
          <item>Protocol: The "AI sprint" method (90-minute focused blocks)</item>
          <item>Common failure modes: using AI as procrastination, over-delegation</item>
        </requirements>
      </technique_deep_dive>

      <pros_cons_when_where>
        <requirements>
          <item>When AI assistance enhances deep work (research, outlining)</item>
          <item>When AI assistance fragments deep work (mid-thought queries)</item>
          <item>Anti-patterns: AI as thinking crutch, context-switching loops</item>
        </requirements>
      </pros_cons_when_where>

      <use_cases_and_examples>
        <requirements>
          <item>Example 1: Developer using Copilot without breaking flow</item>
          <item>Example 2: Writer using ChatGPT for research vs. drafting</item>
          <item>Edge case: The "AI pair programming" paradox</item>
        </requirements>
      </use_cases_and_examples>

      <applicability_and_potential>
        <requirements>
          <item>Three protocols to try this week (with specific instructions)</item>
          <item>Signs you're doing it right vs. signs you need to adjust</item>
          <item>How to design your own AI-augmented deep work practice</item>
        </requirements>
      </applicability_and_potential>

      <whats_next>
        <requirements>
          <item>How "agentic AI" will further change the calculus</item>
          <item>Skills that remain uniquely human (for now)</item>
          <item>Open questions: memory, creativity, and outsourced cognition</item>
        </requirements>
      </whats_next>
    </section_requirements>

    <length>
      Aim for 2000-3000 words. Prefer completeness over brevity, but avoid filler.
    </length>
  </output_contract>
</prompt>
