<prompt>
  <!--
    Example 18.3: Marketing - B2B Content Strategy Deep Dive
    Uses the longform template for comprehensive marketing strategy content
  -->

  <task>
    Write a long-form content piece that dives deep into the topic below.
    The piece should be rigorous, coherent, and concrete.
  </task>

  <topic>Bottom-of-Funnel Content: Why Most B2B SaaS Companies Get It Wrong</topic>

  <audience>B2B SaaS marketing leaders and content strategists</audience>

  <intent>persuade</intent>

  <stance>skeptical</stance>

  <voice_and_tone>
    <style>Modern, restrained, and clear.</style>
    <avoid>
      <item>Marketing buzzwords (leverage, synergy, best-in-class)</item>
      <item>Vague generalities and platitudes</item>
      <item>Overconfident claims without support</item>
      <item>Dismissive tone toward common practices</item>
    </avoid>
  </voice_and_tone>

  <source_policy>
    <policy>
      Draw on observable patterns in B2B SaaS marketing, not proprietary data.
      Use hypothetical examples based on common scenarios.
    </policy>
    <policy>
      Acknowledge that what works varies by market, ACV, and sales cycle.
      Avoid universal prescriptions.
    </policy>
  </source_policy>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Start by defining BOFU content and why it matters to revenue.</constraint>
    <constraint>Use the "buyer's remaining questions" framework to organize the analysis.</constraint>
    <constraint>Include specific content formats with examples (not just "case studies").</constraint>
    <constraint>Provide a scoring rubric for evaluating existing BOFU content.</constraint>
    <constraint>Address the sales-marketing alignment problem explicitly.</constraint>

    <constraint>Introduce key terms (BOFU, MQL, SQL, ACV) before using them.</constraint>
    <constraint>Distinguish between correlation and causation in content performance.</constraint>
    <constraint>Avoid name-dropping; only cite concepts/people if they add explanatory value.</constraint>

    <constraint>Use the exact section headings specified in output_contract.</constraint>
    <constraint>No preamble, no meta-commentary about the prompt.</constraint>
    <constraint>Keep paragraphs reasonably short; prefer clarity over density.</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <optional_context>
    The reader's company likely has plenty of top-of-funnel content (blogs, podcasts)
    but struggles to convert qualified leads. Sales complains that leads "aren't ready."
    The reader needs to build a case for investing in BOFU content to their CMO.
  </optional_context>

  <reader_promises>
    <promise>The reader can identify gaps in their current BOFU content strategy.</promise>
    <promise>The reader has 5 specific content formats to evaluate for their context.</promise>
    <promise>The reader can build a business case for BOFU content investment.</promise>
  </reader_promises>

  <output_contract>
    <format>
      Use markdown with H2 section headings exactly as written below.
      Under each heading, write substantive content (not bullet-only sections).
    </format>

    <required_headings>
      <heading>Introduction and explanation</heading>
      <heading>Technique deep dive</heading>
      <heading>Pros and cons, when and where to use</heading>
      <heading>Use cases and examples</heading>
      <heading>Applicability and potential</heading>
      <heading>What's next</heading>
    </required_headings>

    <section_requirements>
      <introduction_and_explanation>
        <requirements>
          <item>Define BOFU content and its role in the buyer journey</item>
          <item>Explain why companies under-invest (easier metrics at top of funnel)</item>
          <item>Preview the "buyer's remaining questions" framework</item>
        </requirements>
      </introduction_and_explanation>

      <technique_deep_dive>
        <requirements>
          <item>The five questions buyers have before signing (with content that answers each)</item>
          <item>Why "case studies" often fail (and what to do instead)</item>
          <item>The technical evaluation content gap (ROI calculators, implementation guides)</item>
          <item>Common failure modes: too salesy, too vague, wrong stakeholder</item>
        </requirements>
      </technique_deep_dive>

      <pros_cons_when_where>
        <requirements>
          <item>When BOFU investment has highest ROI (long sales cycles, high ACV)</item>
          <item>When TOFU focus makes more sense (volume plays, self-serve)</item>
          <item>Anti-patterns: gating everything, ignoring sales feedback</item>
        </requirements>
      </pros_cons_when_where>

      <use_cases_and_examples>
        <requirements>
          <item>Example 1: Comparison page that actually converts (structure breakdown)</item>
          <item>Example 2: Technical implementation guide as deal accelerator</item>
          <item>Edge case: BOFU content for multi-stakeholder buying committees</item>
        </requirements>
      </use_cases_and_examples>

      <applicability_and_potential>
        <requirements>
          <item>BOFU content scoring rubric (5 criteria with rating scale)</item>
          <item>How to align with sales on content priorities</item>
          <item>Metrics that actually matter (influenced pipeline, not pageviews)</item>
        </requirements>
      </applicability_and_potential>

      <whats_next>
        <requirements>
          <item>AI-generated personalized BOFU content</item>
          <item>Interactive content and product-led BOFU</item>
          <item>Open questions: attribution and measuring true impact</item>
        </requirements>
      </whats_next>
    </section_requirements>

    <length>
      Aim for 2500-3500 words. Prefer completeness over brevity, but avoid filler.
    </length>
  </output_contract>
</prompt>
