<prompt>
  <!--
    Example 18.1: Technical - Deep Dive on Microservices Architecture
    Uses the longform template for comprehensive technical content
  -->

  <task>
    Write a long-form content piece that dives deep into the topic below.
    The piece should be rigorous, coherent, and concrete.
  </task>

  <topic>Microservices Architecture: When Monoliths Make More Sense</topic>

  <audience>Technical leaders and senior engineers evaluating architecture decisions</audience>

  <intent>compare</intent>

  <stance>dialectical</stance>

  <voice_and_tone>
    <style>Modern, restrained, and clear.</style>
    <avoid>
      <item>Hype and marketing language</item>
      <item>Vague generalities</item>
      <item>Overconfident claims without support</item>
      <item>Dismissive statements about either approach</item>
    </avoid>
  </voice_and_tone>

  <source_policy>
    <policy>
      Draw on well-known industry examples (Netflix, Amazon, Segment's return to monolith).
      Present these as illustrative cases, not definitive proof.
    </policy>
    <policy>
      Distinguish between theoretical benefits and observed outcomes in practice.
    </policy>
  </source_policy>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Start by defining both microservices and monoliths in plain language.</constraint>
    <constraint>Use the "Total Cost of Ownership" framework to organize trade-offs.</constraint>
    <constraint>Include both team-size and technical complexity as decision factors.</constraint>
    <constraint>Provide a concrete decision tree or rubric for choosing between approaches.</constraint>
    <constraint>Address the "distributed monolith" anti-pattern explicitly.</constraint>

    <constraint>Introduce key terms (service mesh, eventual consistency, etc.) before using them.</constraint>
    <constraint>Distinguish between: (a) established facts, (b) reasonable inference, (c) speculation.</constraint>
    <constraint>Avoid name-dropping; only cite concepts/people if they add explanatory value.</constraint>

    <constraint>Use the exact section headings specified in output_contract.</constraint>
    <constraint>No preamble, no meta-commentary about the prompt.</constraint>
    <constraint>Keep paragraphs reasonably short; prefer clarity over density.</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <optional_context>
    Focus on organizations with 5-50 engineers, where the decision is most consequential.
    The reader is likely facing pressure to adopt microservices and needs ammunition
    for a nuanced conversation with stakeholders.
  </optional_context>

  <reader_promises>
    <promise>The reader can articulate specific conditions where monoliths outperform microservices.</promise>
    <promise>The reader can identify warning signs of premature microservice adoption.</promise>
    <promise>The reader has a framework for making the decision in their own context.</promise>
  </reader_promises>

  <output_contract>
    <format>
      Use markdown with H2 section headings exactly as written below.
      Under each heading, write substantive content (not bullet-only sections).
    </format>

    <required_headings>
      <heading>Introduction and explanation</heading>
      <heading>Technique deep dive</heading>
      <heading>Pros and cons, when and where to use</heading>
      <heading>Use cases and examples</heading>
      <heading>Applicability and potential</heading>
      <heading>What's next</heading>
    </required_headings>

    <section_requirements>
      <introduction_and_explanation>
        <requirements>
          <item>Define microservices and monoliths without jargon</item>
          <item>Explain why this decision matters (cost, velocity, reliability)</item>
          <item>Preview the Total Cost of Ownership framework</item>
        </requirements>
      </introduction_and_explanation>

      <technique_deep_dive>
        <requirements>
          <item>Break down operational costs: deployment, monitoring, debugging</item>
          <item>Describe the "distributed monolith" failure mode</item>
          <item>Walk through a realistic migration scenario end-to-end</item>
        </requirements>
      </technique_deep_dive>

      <pros_cons_when_where>
        <requirements>
          <item>Team size thresholds (when coordination cost exceeds benefit)</item>
          <item>Technical complexity thresholds (when distribution adds more than it solves)</item>
          <item>Anti-patterns: resume-driven development, premature optimization</item>
        </requirements>
      </pros_cons_when_where>

      <use_cases_and_examples>
        <requirements>
          <item>Example 1: Successful microservices (what made it work)</item>
          <item>Example 2: Failed migration / return to monolith (what went wrong)</item>
          <item>Edge case: The modular monolith as middle ground</item>
        </requirements>
      </use_cases_and_examples>

      <applicability_and_potential>
        <requirements>
          <item>Decision rubric: 5 questions to answer before choosing</item>
          <item>Where monolith-first is the dominant strategy</item>
          <item>What capabilities microservices unlock that can't be achieved otherwise</item>
        </requirements>
      </applicability_and_potential>

      <whats_next>
        <requirements>
          <item>Emerging patterns: modular monoliths, serverless, cell-based architecture</item>
          <item>Next steps for a team currently on a monolith</item>
          <item>Open questions: how AI-assisted development changes the calculus</item>
        </requirements>
      </whats_next>
    </section_requirements>

    <length>
      Aim for 2500-3500 words. Prefer completeness over brevity, but avoid filler.
    </length>
  </output_contract>
</prompt>
